Abdullah Pharaon

Full Stack
Web Developer

Abdullah Pharaon

Toronto, ON

647.444.2435 abdullah.pharaon@gmail.com abdullahonline.co

Motivation

My eyes are set on the future. I am passionate about the intersection between engineering, technology and the human experience. I enjoy exploring different ways technology increasingly integrates in our daily lives and I am thrilled to be a part of it.

Experience

Enginuity Group Corp. (HoodQ) / Software Developer Intern

Mar 2015 - May 2015, Toronto, ON

RoR, Javascript, PostgreSQL, HAML, Git

At HoodQ, I was introduced to the real world workflow of application development. I improved my communication skills when I described technical issues to non-technical folk. I came to appreciate the importance of continuous integration in detecting conflicts early. I became comfortable working and getting familiar with a large codebase and spec suite written by others. I identified and resolved bugs and worked on features and the API. Major areas covered: mailers, maps, tests and database querying.

SNC-Lavalin | Mining & Metallurgy/ Package Engineer

Apr 2013 - Jan 2014, Montreal, QC

At SNC, I identified common processes across projects and developed standards and procedure manuals used division-wide. I made recommendations for contracting strategies by analyzing past performance. I contributed to the development of an Automated Workflow system to be used for preparing and verifying engineering documents, set to reduce the process on the order of weeks. Through dispute resolution, I got heavy exposure to contracts and scrutinized whether client change requests fell within the scope of work or not, thus determining if they warranted additional resources.

USS Cal Builders / On-site Construction Management Intern

May 2010 - Aug 2010, Los Angeles, CA

At USS, I facilitated frequent communication between all stakeholders and learned the importance of such activity. I compiled daily reports monitoring all parties involved. I recognised the value of transparency and documentation in maintaining accountability.

Education

Bitmaker Labs / Immersive Full-Time Web Development Bootcamp

OCT 2014 - DEC 2014, Toronto, ON

City University London/ MSc Construction Management

2011 - 2012, London, UK

University of Southern California/ BS Civil Engineering

2007 - 2011, Los Angeles, CA

Skills

Comfortable grasp of **Object Oriented Programming**. Working knowledge of developing interactive web applications with **Ruby on Rails** supported by a **SQL** database (**MySQL**, **PostgreSQL**, **SQLite**). Interested in adding to **Javascript** expertise (**JQuery**, **AJAX**) by exploring front-end frameworks and using Javascript across the stack.